Legends never die
The Legend of Ben Hall is a western film directed by Matthew Holmes.
Ben Hall is drawn back into bushranging by the
reappearance of his old friend John Gilbert.
Reforming the gang, they soon become the most wanted men in Australian history.
Ben Hall, played by Jack Martin.
Daniel Ryan, played by Callan McAuliffe.
Edward Morriss, played by Arthur Angel.
Billy Dargin, played by Angus Pilakui.
Old Man Gordon, played by Andy McPhee.
Eliza Mensey, played by Fantine Banulski.
The Legend of Ben Hall is a 2016 Australian bushranger film.
Written and directed by Matthew Holmes, it is based on the
exploits of bushranger Ben Hall and his gang.
The film stars Jack Martin in the title role, Jamie Coffa as
John Gilbert, and William Lee as John Dunn.
The film focuses on the last nine months of Hall's life, when he was a
well-established bushranger along with his accomplices Gilbert and Dunn.
It explores the relationships within the gang and depicts many
of their robberies and clashes with the police.
The film also explores the details surrounding Hall's betrayal and his
controversial death at the hands of the police on 5 May 1865.
The film premiered at Forbes before traveling to film
festivals in Australia and overseas.
It received mixed reviews from critics although its
historical accuracy was praised.
The film explores themes of australia, biography,
revisionist history, new south wales, bushranger.